Ricardo Gonzalez

Easton, MA, 02375 | +15082129147 gonzalezr@merrimack.edu

Profile

Motivated young professional with a strong work ethic, backend development, UI development, and database experience. Able to be self-sufficient on a project or work alongside a team, and a fire to learn more every day!

Interests: Learning new technologies, reading, traveling, environment preservation, videography, physical training, and investing

Accomplishments: Designed a Web Application used by people worldwide. Created a game with an interactive UI using Object Oriented Design techniques.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

Jan 2022 - Present

Athena Health, Watertown, MA

- I develop new key sfeatures using TypeScript/JS within the React Framework, for our customer's wants and needs
- I ensure the product has 100% code coverage by providing every feature is paired with automated tests, written in Java using the Selenium testing suite
- I worked with multiple product developments teams to reach company goals

Software Engineer

Jun 2019 - Sep 2021

Olympus Scientific Solutions, Waltham, MA

- Led and owned the development of a web application using Angular in order to enable the sale of our latest product.
- I communicated and gathered requirements from our product owners and direct customers to ensure the beta web application was perfect for our customers
- I made the initiative to have our product well-tested by creating Java E2E tests on my new application
- Using C++ and Java I developed and maintained new features on all our microservice, exceeding our customer's wants
- Improved team productivity and efficiency by implementing Agile Methodologies

Software Developer

Aug 2018 - Dec 2019

IBM, The Weather Company, Andover, MA

- I designed a library that verifies user credentials that can be passed onto all our microservices, to improve in house apps and daily developer efficiency
- I created a web application that uses Amazon's API and EC2 services, in order to manage our Load Balancers in real-time utilizing microservices

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Aug 2015 - May 2019

Merrimack College, North Andover, MA

Relevant Courses: Object-Oriented Programming, Theory of Computation, Database Principles, Operating Systems, Data Structures